ASHISH BARAVALIYA

<u>ashishbarvaliya.job@gmail.com</u> | <u>ashishbaravaliya.com</u> | Sarnia, ON

Profile

I am an experienced **full-stack developer** with over **3 years** of work experience in a multinational corporation in India, just completed my post-graduation studies in **full-stack software development** from Lambton College. Additionally, working as a **full-stack developer** for freelance projects on a part-time basis, I also contribute to **open-source** projects for platforms like <u>Parse Community</u> and <u>Directus</u> among others.

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/ashishbarvaliya</u> GitHub: <u>github.com/AshishBarvaliya</u>

Skills

Languages: JavaScript, Typescript, Python, C#, HTML, Java

Frameworks: React.js, Next.js, Vue.Js, Spring Boot **Tools:** Azure, AWS, Git, Docker, Firebase, GCP

Frontend: MUI, Tailwind CSS, Styled-component, Storybook, SCSS, Ant Design

Backend: Node, SQL, .NET, GraphQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Prisma ORM, Drizzle ORM

Soft Skills: Problem solving, Quick learner, Team player, Creativity.

Work History

Freelance Remote, Canada

Full Stack Engineer

August 2022 - Present

- Managing a SAAS marketplace web app single-handedly in a small startup, including overseeing all
 aspects of its development and operation
- Completed over five projects, including OpenAI apis, a payment invoice page, and a database management system. Each project involved utilizing a diverse range of skills, including front-end and back-end development.
- Gained proficiency in various areas including Next.js, Ant Design, Tailwind CSS, Docker, AWS, Stripe,
 Netlify CMS, and Team leading.

Kerv Digital Bengaluru, India

Full Stack Developer

December 2019 - August 2022

- In the role of a frontend developer for **2.5+ years**, responsibilities included implementing frontend designs, collaborating with teams to **deliver high-quality results**, and **presenting** work to clients.
- Developed a web portal for LearnLight with React, TypeScript and Apollo GraphQL. The portal allows LearnLight users to view profile information, keep track of learning resources and activities.
- Developed web portal with a big team for the Scouts of UK. The portal enables users to apply for permits and effectively manage profiles. utilized React, Styled Components, Redux Toolkit, and Azure to deliver a seamless user experience.

Education

Lambton College

September 2022 - April 2024

Post-Graduation in Full Stack Software Development 3.5/4.0

Gujarat Technological University Bachelors in information technology 7.5/10 August 2015 - May -2019

Projects

Theme AI (Product) [2024]

- Launched this own product in 2024.
- Product "Select AI-Enhanced Meaningful Themes for Your Web Design"
- Tech stack Typescript, Next.js, ShadCn, Drizzle ORM, PostgreSQL, Stripe, Next Auth.
- Monthly new users ~200 and Page view ~2000.
- https://www.themeai.io/

Portfolio app [2023]

- Created my portfolio website using Reactjs, SCSS with Sanity CMS.
- <u>github.com/AshishBarvaliya/portfolio-web</u>

LetterLinc [2023]

- Utilize advanced AI to create personalized cover letters based on your resume and job description.
- Skills showcase React, Typescript, TailwindCSS, OpenAI, Firebase
- github.com/AshishBarvaliya/LetterLinc

Gesture Based Home Automation [2019]

- Created a home automation system using raspberry pi, python, and computer vision, can be used by people with disabilities (mute and deaf) to control home appliances by making a few hand gestures to the camera.
- github.com/AshishBarvaliya/Hand-gesture-detection

Certifications

Python Programming Bible: Python, oops concepts, and Data structure **Project Management Simplified:** Agile, Scrum, Jira, and Grant chat. **Machine learning with python by Andrew Ng:** Al and ML Algorithms

Deep learning Specialization by Andrew Ng: Neural Network, Computer Vision, and NLP